# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, I am Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道拿手菜
In this video, I am sharing with you the dish I am very good at
# 电饭锅红烧肉
Rice cooker red braised pork
# 首先我们准备新鲜且富有弹性的五花肉一大块
First, we prepare a large piece of fresh and bouncy pork belly
# 不喜欢五花肉的同学也可以选择二刀肉
If you don’t like pork belly, you can also choose pork hind leg top cut
# 然后在托盘中加入适量的清水
Then we add some water into the tray
# 下一步开始烧皮
Next, we start torching the skin
# 首先用喷枪把猪皮烧至焦黑色
We will torch and burn the skin to black color first
# 第一遍是去除猪毛
The first time is to remove the hair
# 第二遍是烧至皮黄
The second time is to torch the skin until it is yellow
# 第三遍才是烧至焦黑
The third time is to torch it until it is black
# 托盘中加水的目的是防止托盘受热变形
Adding water in the tray is to prevent the tray to deform while being heated
# 烧至焦黑之后用钢丝球或者菜刀
After torching it black, we use stainless steel scrubber or knife
# 将烧焦的部分刮洗干净
To remove the burnt part and wash it clean
# 刮洗干净之后开始分肉
After cleaning the meat, we can start dividing the meat
# 首先带乳头的部分容易分层
First, the part that has nipples is very easy to split between layers
# 但瘦肉比较多
But it has a lot of lean meat
# 最后的部分肥肉比较厚重
The last part has a lot more fat
# 而中间部分则不肥不瘦比较紧实
The middles part is not too lean or too fat, very firm
# 然后我们取中间部分下一步开始煮肉
Then we will take the middle part to continue cooking
# 将五花肉放入电饭锅中加入适量的清水
Put the pork belly into rick cooker and add some water
# 加入适量的红酒
Add some red wine
# 准备大葱两根切成小段加入
Prepare a couple spring onions, add them in after cut them into small pieces
# 准备生姜一小块切成姜片备用
Prepare a small piece of ginger and slice them for later use
# 然后接上电源将五花肉煮至断生
Then power it up and cook the pork belly
# 此过程根据不同的电饭锅煮制的时间也不同
This process could take various length of time depending on which rice cooker you use
# 大约20分钟之后用筷子能插透即可捞出
In about 20 mins later, you can take the meat out if chopsticks can penetrate it
# 猪肉捞出之后均匀的撒上适量的食用盐
Put some salt on the pork after taking it out
# 下一步开始准备炸皮
Next, we start to fry the skin
# 首先我们把锅烧热
We heat up the wok first
# 锅烧热之后加入一勺植物油烧热
After the wok is heated, we can add a scoop of vegetable oil
# 油温烧至六成热之后将猪皮朝下炸至金黄色
When the oil is about 180 Celsius, we can put the pork in skin down until its golden brown
# 这一步的目的是保证红烧肉软而皮不烂
This step is to make sure the red braised pork will be soft, but the skin doesn’t fall apart
# 炸至金黄色之后捞出皮朝下放入托盘中
After it is golden brown, put it on the tray skin down
# 然后准备一个小托盘压在上面
Then prepare another smaller tray on top of it
# 也可以用重物或者胶带缠紧
You can also use heavy object or tape to tighten it
# 猪肉压紧之后放入冰箱冰冻一个小时
After pressing the pork firm, you can put it into the freezer for an hour
# 这一步的目的是防止猪肉下锅热胀冷缩导致变形
This step is to prevent the pork expand or shrink due to change of the temperature, resulting in deforming of the pork belly
# 冰冻一个小时之后将肉取出切成小方块备用
After freezing for an hour, take the meat out and cut them into small cubes
# 理论上切得越大
Theoretically, the bigger you cut them
# 则烧得越久
It will take longer to braise
# 相反切得越小块时间则越短
On the contrary, the smaller you cut them, the shorter it takes to braise them
# 然后将切好的猪肉放入锅中
Then put the pork cubes you cut into the cooker
# 准备生姜一小块拍散备用
Prepare a small ginger and smash it for later use
# 准备大葱两根切成小段备用
Prepare a couple spring onions into small piece for later use
# 锅中加入适量的清水
Add some water into the cooker
# 水的量需要参考电饭锅的火力
The amount of water you need to consider the heat rice cooker can generate
# 以及水分蒸发的时间等等
And the time it takes for the water to evaporate
# 锅中加入少许的姜葱油
Adding a little ginger scallion oil
# 没有姜葱油的同学也可以不加
If you do not have ginger scallion oil, it’s fine if you don’t add it
# 加入冰糖一小块
Add a small piece of white rock sugar
# 加入红酒60克
Add 60g of red wine
# 没有红酒的同学也可以用黄酒或者料酒代替
If you don’t have red wine, you can also use huangjiu rice wine or Chinese cooking wine
# 加入糖色10克
Add 10g of caramelized sugar
# 最后加入桂皮两小块
At the end, add a couple pieces of cinnamon
# 然后盖上盖子煮120分钟
Then cover it and cook it for 120 minutes
# 烧至60分钟的时候捡去姜葱香料不要
After cooking for 60 minutes, remove the ginger, spring onions and other ingredients
# 然后加入适量的食用盐调咸味
Then add some salt for saltiness
# 调好味之后继续烧剩余的时间
After adjusting the flavor, I will continue to cook for the rest of the 120 minutes
# 中途需要定时揭开锅盖查看水量是否烧干
While cooking, we need to open the cooker and check if majority of the water are evaporated every now and then
# 烧够两个小时之后水分略干且汤汁浓稠即可出锅
After 2 hours, when the water is mostly evaporated and the sauce is very thick, we can take the meat out
# 同学们汤汁是否浓稠
Everyone you know, whether or not the sauce is thick
# 除了肉胶的作用之外
Not only because of the effect of the collagen in the meat
# 冰糖也起到了很大的作用
But also because of the white rock sugar
# 然后准备烧热的小石锅一个
Then prepare a small hot stone pot
# 加入焯好水的西兰花垫底
Add some blanched broccoli in the bottom
# 同学们选用烧热的石锅可以增加成菜的保温时间
Everyone, the reason I choose a hot stone pot is because it can keep the dish warm for a while
# 没有石锅的同学也可以选用砂锅
If you do not have a stone pot you can also use a clay pot
# 蔬菜垫底之后依次加入红烧肉
After putting the vegetables on the bottom, then you can add the red braised pork on top of them
# 最后淋上剩余的汤汁即可上菜
At the end, pour the sauce over the dish then we present it
# 一道肥而不腻的电饭锅红烧肉就制作完成
A fat but not greasy rice cooker red braised pork is finished
# 下面开始技术总结
Now here are the technical summary
# 第一五花肉部位的选择
First is how we choose the pork belly cut
# 五花肉边上带乳头的部位比较瘦
The side of the pork belly with nipples is leaner
# 但肉比较松容易脱层影响美观
But the meat is loose and easy to split between layers
# 同样最后的位置肉最Q弹
And the back part of the pork belly is very tender
# 但肥肉最多很容易腻口
But it has the fattest meat so it got greasy very fast
# 中间的五花肉肥瘦参半
The middle part of pork belly is balanced with fat and lean meat
# 且不脱层
And it is not that easy to split between layers
# 所以比较适合红烧肉的原料是
So, the cut that fit red braised pork is
# 不肥不瘦的中间部位
The middle part that is well balance with far and lean meat
# 第二
Secondly
# 电饭锅火力虽然小
Although rice cooker can not generate a lot of heat
# 但是很容易将猪肉烧透
But it is easy to fully cook the pork
# 口感上来说比高压锅出品更加弹牙
And the texture is better than the ones cooked by high pressure cooker
# 家庭长时间炖肉容易被遗忘
Cooking it for a long time at home, it’s easy to forget the meat is still cooking
# 而电饭锅也可以自动跳闸也显得更加的安全
And the rice cooker can automatically stop cooking so it is safer this way
# 第三
Third
# 炸肉之前可以先涂抹一层食用盐
Before frying the meat, we can rub some salt on the surface
# 这样可以防止猪肉油脂爆炸
This way we can prevent the oil to splash while frying
# 即使猪肉很肥下锅也不容易炸锅
Even when the meat is very fatty, it is not easy to splash while frying
# 下面进行不抹盐下锅测试
Now let’s make an experiment without rubbing the salt on it
# 大家可以很显然的感受到
We can obviously feel that
# 猪肉的油脂已经炸裂
The oil in the pork is already burst
# 同学们这一步比较危险
This step is very dangerous
# 请勿模仿
Please don’t do this at home
# 肉皮经过油炸之后即使烧很长时间也能够保持原型不烂
After frying the skin, even if we braise the pork for a long time, the cube will stay in shape
# 第四
Fourth
# 未加冰冻的肉也可以直接切块烧
You can also braise the unfrozen meat
# 但猪肉会热胀冷缩导致成品膨胀不方正
But the pork will deform due the change of the temperature
# 解决这个问题最好的方法就是用
The best solution for this problem is
# 重物平压冰冻一个小时
To use heavy object to hold it down in the freezer for an hour
# 这样操作过的红烧肉显得方方正正
After this, the red braised pork will stay in shape as a neat cube
# 且不影响口感
It won’t affect the texture
# 以下大家可以看一下对比
Here is the comparison for you
# 第五
Fifth
# 加红酒烧肉可以分解肥肉中的油脂
Adding alcohol here is to wash down the grease
# 红酒加得越多则越不容易腻
The more wine you add, the less greasy the pork will taste like
# 在最后吃的时候可以配上酸萝卜和红酒
At then end when you eat it, you can eat it with pickled radish and red wine
# 这样也可以解腻
This is good for washing down the grease too
# 红烧肉的技术总结完毕
This is the end of technical summary in red braised pork